Finding Aid for the Wilbur Fisk Tillett Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Wilbur Fisk Tillett Collection
1875-1936
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0457
2.1 linear feet
BIOGRAPHY/HISTORY
Wilbur Fisk Tillett (1854-1936) was born in Hendersonville, North Carolina. He graduated from, Randolph-Macon College (now Duke University) in 1877; In 1879, he received a Master of Arts from Princeton University, and graduated from the Princeton Theological Seminary in 1880. Subsequently, he received doctor’s degrees from Randolph-Macon, Wesleyan, Southwestern and Northwestern.
In 1882, he began his teaching career at Vanderbilt as the first Chaplain of the University as well as teacher of Systematic Theology. He later became Dean of the Vanderbilt School of Religion
During his lifetime, he published many books on Christian doctrine and Methodism.
SCOPE AND CONTENTS
This.21 linear feet collection, in 23 file folders, contains family correspondence Wilbur Tillett received from several family members, postcards, poems, and a pamphlet. The correspondence is arranged in chronological order.
- Correspondence
  - 1875
  - 1876
  - 1877
  - 1881
  - 1888
  - 1889
  - 2 letters, 1893
  - 1894
  - 6 letters, 1895
  - 11 letters, 1896
  - 4 letters, 1897
  - 2 letters, 1899
  - 1901
  - 1902
  - 1906
  - 6 letters, 1907
  - 13 letters, 1908
  - n.d.
- Correspondence - Postcards
  - 1921
- Pamphlet
  - ‘Our Doctrinal Standards’
    - by Rev. Richard Green
      - (handwritten notes on the last page)
- Poem
  - ‘To Dr. Wilbur Fisk Tillett’
    - by Costen H. Harrell
      - Read at Dr. Tillett’s funeral on June 5, 1936
- Publisher Information, 1905
- Teaching Materials - Quiz
  - Questions for “A Floral Love Story”, n.d